Alright, we'll go to the search bar type glue here.
Click on AWS glue, then go to the left, left hand side
and click on a L Jobs.
Then go to script data.
Click on this particular button here.
Now choose Python shell.
Now to know more about the glue jobs, the Python shell
that you are seeing here, watch my deep dive course
now click on click Create script name this job as mission.
D-H-H-F-N-Y-C-T-L-C.
Ingestion job, which ingesting the N-Y-C-T-L-C data.
Next you go to get the script.
Write below this video or upload this video.
You'll have my script. Download that
and open that in your editor.
Copy the whole script and right here, paste it,
then save this.
Go to job details, scroll down.
Now this Im role was created by the script you ran before
and in the real world, this will be given to you
by your team lead or your team members.
So we'll choose Mission dh, HOF, blue Service role.
You will then simply save it and then click on run.
So it says successfully start the
job, navigate to run details.
So click on this and it's currently running right now.
This will take about six minutes While this is
running, go to the S3 bucket.
You had the data here already, right?
The one file which you had uploaded manually delete this.
We just copy this permanently, delete right here
and paste it here and delete.
So that file is gone. Now, we'll again, click on the source.
You see what's happening here. We had not
created this folder here.
Okay, I told you in Data Lake we can organize the
folders depending on how we want, right?
And now what are we doing here?
We're trying to get data from 2025
and 2024 for the different months.
So we wanna organize the data by the year and by month.
So we are now gonna be organizing in this format and,
and the code is doing that.
The code that is running in the glue job that
before it uploads the data, it's gonna be making sure
that the folders like these are created.
So within that you'll see you also have month folders.
And within that you're gonna have the data file.
If I just do a refresh, you'll see even 11
here in a few seconds.
There you go. The 11 has come here.
Now let's go back to the job. Click on the runs.
Here it is still running by the way,
this will take about six minutes.
Okay, scroll down a bit.
Click on the output logs here, right here and here.
If you scroll down, click on this log stream, okay?
You'll see the log getting streamed
to this cloud Watch right here.
Okay. Now the, our Python job is actually printing the log
and the log is getting captured in this service
called US CloudWatch.
CloudWatch is the center hub for all the logs in AWS.
So they're still running. By the way, if I go back to S3,
I'll go back to one level up
and you will see that year 2025 folder has also got created.
We go inside and we see three folders here.
Now remember the use case was to not just get this data,
we also wanted to get the taxi
Zone lookup file, right?
That will also get downloaded and populated in history or
after this is populated.
Now organizing the data in this format
is actually called as partitioning.
Okay? We are partitioning the data in our data lake.
This is one of the main techniques to improve performance
when the data is queried on the data lake, right?
Data is getting stored here.
Now obviously the data analysts will query from Athena
and data will get read from these, this data lake.
When you have a partitions like this
and when they use filters such as year equal to 95
and monthly equal to zero one,
only this particular file data will get scanned, okay?
And the results will be, uh,
displayed on the Athena UI from this file alone
because the filter had it that year equal to 2 95
and month equal to zero one.
Okay? Now I'm talking about filter and stuff.
Again, this is a common uh, SQL thing.
If you don't know about sql, I highly recommend going
to the SQL Skill Boost Booster course
and then, then come here.
'cause SQL is the heart of IT.
Engineering, you have to know sql. But remember that C,
the SQL Skill Booster is not a full fledged SQL course.
SQL course itself can be over 25, 30 hours.
So that will be a part of DI Diamond membership.
But the SQL Skill Booster will immediately help you
understand what is being done right now
in this course, right?
We have all the data for the Edge, we FHV
and we go back to raw.
You will see that we also have a folder called A zone.
And within the zone we have the lookup file here
that our glue job, the Python script pulled, okay?
And if you go back to raw,
you'll see a file called as inges not Done.
I'll talk to you about this later as to
what is a significant risk later in fact.
And if you go back to the Glue job,
it shows succeeded here, right here.
And if you go to the CloudWatch, we scroll down,
they shows the progress is a hundred percent here.
All that. That's it. Our task is done.
We wanted to pull data from the N-Y-C-T-L-C portal
and dump it into the data lake.
So what's the next step? Next step is gonna be helping the
data analyst access this data.
And remember they also said they need
the zone table as well.
So you gotta create a zone table as well in the database.
So let's do that in the next step.